The world this week. Politics.
本周世界大事。政治篇。
Ursula von der Leyen, the European Commission's president, invited Canada to become the European Union's first associate member.
欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩邀请加拿大成为欧盟首个准成员。
In the EU's State of the Union address, she told Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney that the partnership would be "for our common strength".
她在欧盟盟情咨文中对加拿大总理马克·卡尼说，这种伙伴关系将“增强我们共同的力量”。
Canada has sought closer ties to the bloc as its trade war with America worsens.
随着加拿大与美国的贸易战加剧，加拿大一直在寻求与欧盟建立更紧密的联系。
Donald Trump called the proposal "laughable" and threatened the EU with "serious tariffs".
唐纳德·特朗普称这一提议“可笑”，并威胁对欧盟征收“严厉关税”。
Russian drones hit a stationary Ukrainian locomotive and a petrol station near the Polish border, approximately an hour after a train carrying top Western officials passed through the area.
一列载有西方高级官员的火车经过约一小时后，俄罗斯无人机袭击了波兰边境附近一辆停驶的乌克兰机车和一座加油站。
Andriy Sybiha, Ukraine's foreign minister, called the strike "Putin's terror knocking on the doors of the EU and NATO".
乌克兰外长安德里·瑟比加称，这次袭击是“普京的恐怖行径敲响欧盟和北约的大门”。
Magdalena Andersson, the leader of Sweden's Social Democrats, looked likely to become the country's next prime minister after an agonisingly close election on September 13th.
在 9 月 13 日胜负难分的选举后，瑞典社会民主党领导人玛格达莱娜·安德松看来有望成为该国下一任首相。
Ms Andersson's left-wing bloc, which includes small-state centrists, environmentalists and leftist populists, was set to take 176 seats, compared with 173 for the government and its allies.
安德松所在的左翼阵营包括主张小政府的中间派、环保主义者和左翼民粹主义者，预计获得 176 席；政府及其盟友预计获得 173 席。
The populist-right Sweden Democrats, who have supported the centre-right government since 2022, lost support for the first time since they entered parliament in 2010.
自 2022 年以来支持中右翼政府的右翼民粹政党瑞典民主党，自 2010 年进入议会以来首次失去选民支持。
A pair of record-breaking donations to Reform UK prompted calls for an overhaul of funding in British politics.
两笔创纪录的捐款流向英国改革党，引发了改革英国政治献金制度的呼声。
Christopher Harborne and Ben Delo, British crypto-billionaires who used to live in Asia, said they would each give £36 million, or $48 million, to the populist-right party led by Nigel Farage.
曾在亚洲居住的英国加密货币亿万富翁克里斯托弗·哈伯恩和本·德洛表示，两人将各向奈杰尔·法拉奇领导的右翼民粹政党捐出 3600 万英镑，约合 4800 万美元。
Politicians from other parties now want to tighten the rules, perhaps even rendering Reform UK's windfall illegal.
其他政党的政客如今希望收紧规则，甚至可能使英国改革党得到的这笔巨款变得不合法。
Benjamin Netanyahu, Israel's prime minister, said that he would sue Haaretz, a liberal Israeli newspaper, for publishing claims that days before October 7th, 2023, the leader of the United Arab Emirates warned him in a phone call that Hamas, the Islamists in Gaza, were preparing to attack.
以色列总理本雅明·内塔尼亚胡表示将起诉自由派报纸《国土报》。该报称，2023 年 10 月 7 日前几天，阿联酋领导人曾在电话中警告他，加沙的伊斯兰主义组织哈马斯正准备发动袭击。
Mr Netanyahu's office said that the reports were part of a sinister plot, and that the prime minister had received no such warning.
内塔尼亚胡办公室称，这些报道是一场险恶阴谋的一部分，首相并未收到过这样的警告。
The Houthis, Iran-backed rebels in Yemen, advanced down the country's western coast.
受到伊朗支持的也门胡塞武装沿该国西海岸向南推进。
They acquired Mocha, a port city, and seized Perim Island, a rocky outcrop in the middle of the Bab el-Mandeb, the strait that links the Red Sea to the Indian Ocean.
他们控制了港口城市摩卡，并夺取了佩里姆岛。这座多岩石的岛屿位于连接红海与印度洋的曼德海峡中部。
In July, the Houthis announced a blockade on Saudi shipping through the Red Sea.
7 月，胡塞武装宣布封锁沙特船只通过红海。
Meanwhile, drones hit Saudi Arabia's east-west pipeline, which can carry up to seven million barrels per day to the kingdom's Red Sea ports.
与此同时，无人机袭击了沙特的东西向输油管道。这条管道每天最多可向该国红海港口输送 700 万桶石油。
It was shut down as a precautionary measure. The Saudi foreign ministry blamed the attack on militias in Iraq.
出于预防目的，管道已关闭。沙特外交部将袭击归咎于伊拉克境内的民兵组织。
The closure saw the price of Brent crude, the international oil benchmark, rise above $109 a barrel.
管道关闭导致国际原油基准布伦特原油价格升至每桶 109 美元以上。
Saudi Arabia said it shot down a Houthi drone south of the holy city of Mecca.
沙特称在圣城麦加以南击落了一架胡塞武装无人机。
China accused American tech bosses of fearmongering over their calls to limit its ability to develop AI.
中国指责美国科技公司高管呼吁限制其人工智能发展能力是在散播恐慌。
Dario Amodei, the chief executive of Anthropic, called for a slowdown in AI development. He warned that a Chinese lead would pose grave danger for America and the world.
Anthropic 首席执行官达里奥·阿莫代伊呼吁放缓人工智能的发展。他警告说，如果中国取得领先，将给美国和世界带来严重危险。
China's foreign ministry said such comments were counterproductive and would limit options for global AI governance.
中国外交部表示，这类言论适得其反，会限制全球人工智能治理的选择空间。
Donald Trump said America must remain ahead of China in AI as he rejected a chorus of calls for a slowdown and greater regulation.
唐纳德·特朗普表示，美国必须在人工智能领域保持对中国的领先，同时驳回了要求放缓发展和加强监管的呼声。
Steve Bannon, a former Trump adviser, and Bernie Sanders, a socialist Democrat, united in a speech to warn of the need for greater oversight of the technology.
特朗普前顾问史蒂夫·班农和社会主义派民主党人伯尼·桑德斯在一次演讲中共同警告，需要加强对这项技术的监管。
Mr Trump has said "whoever wins AI wins" and dismissed concerns that it poses a risk to humanity as "a hoax".
特朗普曾说“谁赢得人工智能，谁就赢得一切”，并把人工智能威胁人类的担忧斥为“骗局”。
Mr Trump hit out at America's Supreme Court for rejecting his attempt to restrict postal voting ahead of November's midterms.
特朗普抨击美国最高法院，因为法院否决了他在 11 月中期选举前限制邮寄投票的企图。
The president wrote on Truth Social, his social-media platform, that the court was "bullied and cajoled by the radical left". He has repeated claims, without evidence, that postal voting is prone to fraud.
总统在自己的社交媒体平台 Truth Social 上写道，法院“受到激进左派的胁迫和哄骗”。他一再毫无证据地声称，邮寄投票容易出现舞弊。
America's Environmental Protection Agency, or EPA, will scrap limits on greenhouse-gas emissions from coal- and gas-fired power plants.
美国环境保护署将取消燃煤和燃气发电厂的温室气体排放限制。
The head of the EPA said that reversing the Biden administration's requirements that plants reduce pollution using technologies such as carbon capture and storage would save Americans $310 billion.
环保署负责人表示，撤销拜登政府要求发电厂使用碳捕集与封存等技术减少污染的规定，将为美国人节省 3100 亿美元。
Power plants are America's second-biggest source of CO2 emissions.
发电厂是美国第二大二氧化碳排放源。
America paid $725 million in dues to the United Nations, averting the possibility that it could lose its vote in the UN General Assembly for skipping two years' worth of membership fees.
美国向联合国支付了 7.25 亿美元会费，从而避免因连续两年拖欠会费而可能失去在联合国大会投票权的情况。
The payment, made for the 2025 budget, was overdue. The Trump administration had halted contributions to push for changes to some UN agencies and priorities.
这笔属于 2025 年预算的款项此前已逾期。特朗普政府曾暂停缴款，以推动部分联合国机构及其工作重点发生改变。
Police in the Philippines said it could take months to identify victims from a ferry fire that killed at least 76 people.
菲律宾警方表示，一场造成至少 76 人死亡的渡轮火灾，其遇难者身份确认可能需要数月。
The MV June Aster was travelling from Manila to Coron, a popular tourist destination, when the fire broke out. The cause of the blaze has not yet been identified.
“六月紫菀”号渡轮从马尼拉前往热门旅游目的地科隆时起火。火灾原因尚未查明。
China's president, Xi Jinping, attended the BRICS summit in New Delhi on his first trip to India for seven years.
中国国家主席习近平出席了在新德里举行的金砖国家峰会，这是他七年来首次访问印度。
Mr Xi met India's prime minister, Narendra Modi, on the sidelines of the event, in a further warming of relations between the countries following a border dispute in 2020.
习近平在峰会期间会见了印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪。两国关系在 2020 年边境争端后进一步回暖。
Prabowo Subianto, Indonesia's president, appointed his third finance minister in two years.
印度尼西亚总统普拉博沃·苏比延多在两年内任命了第三位财政部长。
Mr Prabowo replaced Purbaya Yudhi Sadewa with his deputy, Suahasil Nazara, in a bid to restore economic credibility.
为恢复经济政策的公信力，普拉博沃以副部长苏阿哈西尔·纳扎拉取代了普尔巴亚·尤迪·萨德瓦。
Mr Purbaya, who was in office for a year, spooked investors by calling the IMF "stupid" and with his comments about the effects of rising oil prices on the global economy.
任职一年的普尔巴亚称国际货币基金组织“愚蠢”，又对油价上涨如何影响全球经济发表言论，令投资者不安。
The UN Security Council voted unanimously to extend the arms embargo on Sudan's western Darfur region for another month.
联合国安理会一致投票决定，将针对苏丹西部达尔富尔地区的武器禁运再延长一个月。
America backed away from forcing a vote to extend the embargo to the whole country.
美国放弃了推动表决将禁运扩大至整个苏丹的做法。
But it said it would not rubber-stamp a further extension of a Darfur-only embargo.
但美国表示，不会不加审议就同意继续延长仅针对达尔富尔的禁运。
The United Arab Emirates, which is accused of sending weapons to the Rapid Support Forces in Darfur in violation of the restrictions, has been lobbying to extend the ban across the whole country.
阿联酋被指违反限制，向达尔富尔的快速支援部队运送武器；它一直游说将禁运扩大到苏丹全国。